（維吉尼亞州匡蒂科附近森林）
《沈默的羔羊》
史達琳！
Starling!
克勞福要見你
Crawford wants to see you in his office.
謝謝
Thank you, sir.
（傷害）
（苦難）
（痛苦）
（喜歡它）
-克麗絲　-你好
- Clarice. - Hey.
（行為科學組）
找克勞福嗎？
Looking for Crawford?
他快回來了，在他的辦公室等一會吧
He should be back soon. Why don't you wait in his office?
（比爾剝下第五個人的皮）
史達琳
Starling.
-克麗絲，早安　-早安，克勞福先生
- Clarice M. Good morning. - Morning, Mr. Crawford.
抱歉突然把你召離課堂
Sorry to pull you off the course at such short notice.
你的導師說你是班裡的高材生
Your instructors say you're in the top quarter of your class.
希望是吧，他們還沒有公佈成績
I hope so. They haven't posted any grades yet.
有一個任務要辦，於是我想起你
A job's come up, and I thought about you.
這不是正式的任務，較像一份有趣的差事
Not a job, really, more of an interesting errand.
坐下
Sit down.
是，長官
Yes, sir.
我記得你出席過，我在維吉尼亞大學的講座
I remember you from my seminar at UVA.
你追問我本局在胡佛年代的，公民權益記錄
You grilled me on the bureau's civil rights record in the Hoover years.
我給了你甲等
I gave you an A.
是甲下
A minus, sir.
雙主修，心理學及犯罪學，以優異成績畢業
Double major, psych and criminology, graduated magna.
在瑞辛格療養院做過夏季實習
Summer internships at the Reitzinger Clinic.
它說你畢業後，想在行為科學組替我工作
It says when you graduate you want to work for me in Behavioral Science.
是的，我很想
Yes, very much, sir. Very much.
我們正在訪問被囚禁的連環殺手
We're interviewing all serial killers in custody...
作變態行為的分析
for a psycho-behavioral profile.
對一些懸案會有很大幫助
It could be a real help in unsolved cases.
他們大都樂意跟我們談
Most of them have been happy to talk to us.
你會否很易受驚的？
Do you spook easily, Starling?
不會
Not yet, sir.
我們最想見的那個人拒絕合作
The one we want most refuses to help.
我想你去精神病院找他
I want you to go after him in the asylum.
那個人是誰？
Who's the subject?
-心理醫生漢尼拔・萊達　-食人狂魔漢尼拔
- The psychiatrist, Hannibal Lecter. - "Hannibal the Cannibal."
我想他不會跟你交談
I don't expect him to talk to you...
但無論如何我們都得嘗試
but I have to be able to say we tried.
若他不合作，我要如實報告
If he won't cooperate, I want straight reporting.
他的容貌和監獄里的狀況如何？
How's he look? How's his cell?
他有沒有素描，繪畫？如果有，他都畫些什麼？
Is he sketching, drawing? If he is, what's he sketching?
這是萊達的檔案...
Here's a dossier on Lecter...
問卷副本和你的身份證
copy of our questionnaire and an I.D. for you.
週三早上八點把你的報告交給我
Have your memo on my desk by 0800, Wednesday.
好的
Okay.
對不起，為什麼這樣急？
Excuse me, sir, but why the urgency?
萊達已經坐牢很多年了
Lecter's been in prison for years.
他和水牛比爾是否有關連？
Is there some connection between him and Buffalo Bill?
但願有，我要你非常留意
I wish there were. Now, I want your full attention, Starling.
-知道　-要非常小心應付漢尼拔・萊達
- Yes, sir. - Be very careful with Hannibal Lecter.
精神病院的奇頓醫生，會給你講解接見程序
Dr. Chilton at the asylum will go over all the physical procedures used.
無論如何不可偏離程序
Do not deviate from them for any reason whatsoever.
你不可向他透露私人事情
You're to tell him nothing personal.
你不想漢尼拔・萊達知道你的思想的
You don't want Hannibal Lecter inside your head.
執行你的任務，但千萬別忘記他的身份
Just do your job but never forget what he is.
是什麼？
And what is that?
他是個魔頭，一個變態狂人
Oh, he's a monster, a pure psychopath.
可以生擒一個已很難得了
It's so rare to capture one alive.
從研究角度來說，萊達是我們最有價值的資產
From a research point of view, Lecter is our most prized asset.
我們有很多探員來這裡的
We get a lot of detectives here...
但我記不起有這樣漂亮的一個
but I must say I can't remember one as attractive.
你會在巴爾的摩過夜嗎？
Will you be in Baltimore overnight?
如果你有適當的嚮導，這可以是個很好玩的城市
Because this can be quite a fun town if you have the right guide.
我肯定這是個了不起的城市
I'm sure this is a great town, Dr. Chilton...
但我要見萊達醫生，下午還要回去報告
but I must talk to Dr. Lecter and report back this afternoon.
是的，那麼我們快點吧
I see. Well, let's make this quick, then.
我們嘗試研究他，但他太高深了，一般的測試都不適用
We've tried to study him, but he's too sophisticated for the standard tests.
他很討厭我們的
Oh, my, does he hate us.
他覺得我是他的報應
He thinks I'm his nemesis.
克勞福真是聰明，他利用你
Crawford's very clever, isn't he, using you?
-什麼意思？　-找個漂亮的女郎來引誘他
- What do you mean, sir? - Pretty young woman to turn him on.
我相信這八年來萊達都沒見過女人，而你正合他的胃口
I don't believe Lecter's seen a woman in eight years, and you are his taste.
恕我直言
So to speak.
我畢業於維吉尼亞大學，它不是一間儀態學校
I graduated from UVA. It's not a charm school.
很好，你該能記著那些規矩了
Good. Then you should be able to remember the rules.
不要觸摸或接近那塊玻璃，只可傳遞柔軟的紙張給他
Do not touch or approach the glass. Pass him nothing but soft paper.
不可有鉛筆或原子筆，紙張上不可有釘書釘或夾子
No pencils or pens, no staples or paper clips in his paper.
只可用那個活動食物架傳送
Use the sliding food carrier, no exceptions.
不可接受他給你的東西
If he passes you anything, do not accept.
-明白嗎？　-明白
- Do you understand? - Yes, I understand, sir.
我讓你看看，為何我們要有這些戒備
I'm going to show you why we insist on such precautions.
在1981年7月8日的下午
On the afternoon of July 8, 1981...
他說胸口痛，被帶往醫療室
he complained of chest pains and was taken to the dispensary.
為方便做心電圖，他的口罩被除下
His mouthpiece was removed for an EKG.
當護士靠近他身邊時，他對她做了這個
When the nurse leaned over him, he did this to her.
醫生們算是重整了她的下顎，救回她一隻眼睛
The doctors managed to reset her jaw, more or less. Save one of her eyes.
即使在他吃她的舌頭時，他的脈搏從沒超過85
His pulse never got above 85, even when he ate her tongue.
-我把他關在這裡　-奇頓醫生
- I keep him in here. - Dr. Chilton.
若萊達覺得你是他的敵人，那麼...
If Lecter feels that you're his enemy, then...
若我單獨去的話，我們運氣可能會好一點
Maybe we'll have more luck if I go by myself.
你認為如何？
What do you think?
你若在我辦公室時提出來，就可省掉我的時間了
You might have suggested this in my office and saved me the time.
是的，但我會錯過了和你同行的樂趣
Yes, sir, but then I would have missed the pleasure of your company, sir.
她完事後帶她出去吧
When she's finished, bring her out.
你好，我是巴尼，他說過了，不要走近那塊玻璃
Hi, I'm Barney. He told you, don't get near the glass?
對，他說過了，我是克麗絲・史達琳
Yes, he did. Clarice Starling.
幸會，你可以把大衣掛在那裡
Nice to meet you. You can hang your coat there if you like.
好的，謝謝你
Okay. Thank you, I will.
他在最盡頭的那個牢房
He's past the others. The last cell.
靠右走吧
You keep to the right.
-我放了一張椅子給你　-很好，謝謝你
- I put out a chair for you. - Yes, that's very good, thank you.
我會看著，你不會有事的
I'll be watching. You'll do fine.
我可以聞到你的私處
I can smell your cunt.
早安
Good morning.
萊達醫生，我叫克麗絲・史達琳，可否跟你談一會？
Dr. Lecter, my name is Clarice Starling. May I speak with you?
你是克勞福的人，是嗎？
You're one of Jack Crawford's, aren't you?
是的
I am, yes.
可否看看你的證件？
May I see your credentials?
當然可以
Certainly.
靠近一點，勞煩你
Closer, please.
近一點
Closer.
一周內後就到期了，你不是真的聯邦調查局探員吧
That expires in one week. You're not real FBI, are you?
我仍在受訓
I'm still in training at the academy.
-克勞福派個見習生來見我？　-是的，我是個學生
- Jack Crawford sent a trainee to me? - Yes, I'm a student.
我是來向你學習的
I'm here to learn from you.
也許你可以決定，我是否夠資格這樣做
Maybe you can decide if I'm qualified enough to do that.
你很不老實呢，史達琳探員
That is rather slippery of you, Agent Starling.
請坐
Sit. Please.
告訴我，邁克斯對你說了什麼？
Now then, tell me. What did Miggs say to you?
隔壁的「多面人邁克斯」
"Multiple Miggs" in the next cell.
他向你發出嘶嘶聲，他說了些什麼？
He hissed at you. What did he say?
他說「我可以聞到你的私處」
He said, "I can smell your cunt."
是吧
I see.
我可聞不到
I myself cannot.
你用愛膚恩潤膚膏
You use Evyan skin cream.
有時你會塗點香水
And sometimes you wear L'Air du Temps.
但今天沒有
But not today.
這些畫是你畫的嗎？
Did you do all these drawings?
那是從觀景樓遠望的大教堂
That is the Duomo, seen from the Belvedere.
你知道佛羅倫斯嗎？
Do you know Florence?
那些細節都是來自記憶的嗎？
All that detail just from memory, sir?
史達琳探員，我只有記憶，沒有景觀
Memory, Agent Starling, is what I have instead of a view.
你可在這份問卷上，給我們一些見解
Perhaps you'd care to lend us your view on this questionnaire, sir.
不...你做得很好
No, no, no. You were doing fine.
你很有禮，而且能容納禮貌
You had been courteous and receptive to courtesy.
你對邁克斯的尷尬說話，也表現得很信任
You had established trust with the embarrassing truth about Miggs.
至於你這份拙劣的問卷
And now this ham-handed segue into your questionnaire.
就不行了
It won't do.
我只是要求你看看它，你做不做隨便你
I'm only asking you to look at this. Either you will or you won't.
對，若克勞福要從學校找人幫忙
Yeah. Jack Crawford must be very busy indeed...
他一定很忙了
if he's recruiting help from the student body.
忙於追捕那個新手水牛比爾吧
Busy hunting that new one, Buffalo Bill.
他真是個壞孩子
What a naughty boy he is.
你可知道為何他，被稱為水牛比爾？
Do you know why he's called "Buffalo Bill"?
請告訴我，報紙上沒有說
Please tell me. The newspapers won't say.
是來自堪薩斯城，凶案組的一個笑話
It started as a joke in Kansas City Homicide.
他們說「這個人喜歡剝他獵物的皮」
They said, "This one likes to skin his humps."
史達琳探員，你認為為什麼...
Why do you think...
他要剝她們的皮？
he removes their skins, Agent Starling?
用你的敏銳來振奮我一下吧
Thrill me with your acumen.
這樣做令他興奮
It excites him.
大部分的連環殺手都會保存受害人身上的東西作為紀念品
Most serial killers keep trophies from their victims.
-我可沒有　-對
- I didn't. - No.
你吃了他們
No, you ate yours.
把那個傳過來吧
You send that through now.
你以為憑這份拙劣的東西，便可以分析我？
You think you can dissect me with this blunt little tool?
不是！我相信你的學識...
No! I thought that your knowledge...
你很有野心，是不是？
You're so ambitious, aren't you?
可知道你拿著那個高級皮包，穿著廉價鞋子像個什麼？
You know what you look like, with your good bag and your cheap shoes?
像個土包子
You look like a rube.
一個乾淨，忙碌，帶點品味的土包子
A well-scrubbed, hustling rube with a little taste.
雖然你衣食無憂地成長...
Nutrition has given you some length of bone...
你不外乎是個白種低下層的人
but you're not more than one generation from white trash...
是不是，史達琳探員？
are you, Agent Starling?
你極力想擺脫口音...
The accent you've tried so desperately to shed...
地道的西維吉尼亞州腔調
pure West Virginia.
你父親是個礦工嗎？
Is your father a coal miner?
那盞燈可有令他滿身臭氣？
Does he stink of the lamp?
我知道那些男孩怎樣迅速搭上你，在汽車後座里亂摸
I know how quickly the boys found you, all those tedious, sticky fumblings...
你卻想著走出去
in the back seats of cars, while you dreamed of getting out.
走去天涯海角
Getting anywhere.
直走到聯邦調查局
Getting all the way to the FBI.
你很有觀察力
You see a lot, doctor.
但你能否用你敏銳的觀察力...
But are you strong enough to point that...
來分析自己？
high-powered perception at yourself?
怎麼樣？
What about it?
不如你探究一下自己，把觀察所得寫下來
Why don't you look at yourself and write down what you see?
或者你害怕這樣做吧
Or maybe you're afraid to.
曾經有一個人口調查員想測試我
A census taker once tried to test me.
我把他的肝配蠶豆吃了
I ate his liver with some fava beans...
還有美味的紅酒呢
and a nice Chianti.
小史達琳，你飛回學校去吧
You fly back to school now, little Starling.
飛吧...
Fly, fly, fly.
我咬我的手腕...
I bit my wrist...
這樣才能死掉
so I could die.
看這些血
Look at the blood!
嚇到你了
Gotcha.
邁克斯！你這個混蛋！
Miggs! You stupid fuck!
史達琳探員！回來！史達琳探員
Agent Starling! Come back! Agent Starling! Agent Starling!
我不會讓那種事情再發生，我討厭不禮貌的
I would not have had that happen. Discourtesy is ugly to me.
-那麼做這個測驗吧　-不做，但我會令你開心的
- Then do this test! - No, but I will make you happy.
-我會給你一個大好機會　-什麼？
- I'll give you a chance at your love. - What?
升職，聽著，你自我反省一下，克麗絲・史達琳
Advancement. Listen. Look deep within yourself, Clarice Starling.
找出我從前的病人莫菲小姐
Go seek out Miss Mofet, an old patient of mine. M-O-F-E-T.
我相信邁克斯不會這麼快發作的...
I don't think Miggs could manage again so soon...
雖然他是瘋的，快去
even though he is crazy. Go now!
你好，比爾
Hi, Bill.
-爸爸　-克麗絲
- Daddy! - Hey, Clarice.
-爸爸，你有沒有抓到壞人？　-沒有，他們跑掉了
- Did you get any bad guys, Daddy? - No, angel. They all got away.
該死
Ah, shoot.
聯邦調查局，舉手，別動！
FBI! Hands up! Don't move!
轉過身來，把雙手放在後面，好的
Turn around. Hands behind your back. Thumbs up.
史達琳，你已經死了
You're dead, Starling.
強生，進入和指揮都做得很好，史達琳，你哪裡有危險？
Johnson, good entry, good command. Starling, where's your danger area?
-在角落　-你有沒有檢查過它？
- In the corner. - Did you check it?
-沒有，長官　-所以你已經死了
- No, sir. - That's why you're dead.
3109？
3-1-0-9?
打破門或窗闖入或者撤退
Breaking doors or windows to enter or exit.
404號規條呢？
Rule 404?
（巴爾的摩心理醫生，獲得最高榮譽）
（著名心理醫生被控謀殺）
（食人狂魔審訊帶來新的恐怖）
克麗絲，你的電話，是教官
Clarice, phone. It's the guru.
克勞福？謝謝，雅戴
Crawford? Thanks, Ardelia.
-史達琳？　-長官
- Starling? - Sir.
邁克斯死了
Miggs is dead.
死了？
Dead?
怎會的？
How?
守衛聽到漢尼拔・萊達下午時對他低聲說話
The orderly heard Lecter whispering to him all afternoon.
他們在夜間巡查時，發現他吞掉自己的舌頭
They found him at bed check. He'd swallowed his tongue.
史達琳？
Starling?
我還在聽，我只是...
Yeah. I'm still here, sir. I just...
我不知道對這件事該有何感想
I don't know how to feel about this.
你不用感想什麼，萊達這樣做只是為了自娛
You don't have to feel any way. Lecter did it to amuse himself.
我明白今天很難受
Look, I know it got ugly today...
但你提到莫菲，有後續行動嗎？
but you mentioned a name, "Mofet." Any follow-up on her?
他在被捕前，把大部分病人的病歷銷毀了
He destroyed most of his patients' histories prior to capture...
所以沒有莫菲的記錄
so there's no record of anyone named Mofet.
我覺得「你自己」這個參考資料，對萊達來說太造作了
But I thought the "yourself' reference was too hokey for Lecter...
我想起他是來自巴爾的摩，便翻查電話簿
so I figured he's from Baltimore, and I looked in the phone book.
那裡有一間叫「你自己」的自助式倉庫
And there's a "Your Self' storage facility...
在巴爾的摩市外圍
right outside of downtown Baltimore, sir.
31號倉已經租了十年...
Unit 31 was leased...
租金是全數預繳的
for 10 years, prepaid in full.
合約是以一個...
The contract was in the name...
是赫斯達・莫菲小姐的人定的
of a Miss Hester Mofet.
自從1980年就沒有人來過了？
So nobody's been in here since 1980?
以我所知是沒有
Not to my knowledge.
我的顧客都很重視私隱權的
Privacy is a great concern to my customers.
對，我答應不會擾亂任何東西
Yes, I won't disturb anything, I promise.
我很快便會離開
I'll be out of here before you know it.
-要幫忙嗎？　-好的
- May I help you? - Yes, actually.
這裡
Here.
-它被卡著　-明天可以叫我的兒子來
- It's stuck. - We could return tomorrow with my son.
他怎麼樣？
What about him?
我本可叫我的司機幫你，但他討厭體力勞動
I would ask my driver to help you, but he detests physical labor.
是吧
Right.
你別走開，我很快回來
You stay here. I'll be back in one minute.
它被卡著，請你把那支電筒給我
It's stuck. Will you hand me that flashlight?
如果這道門跌下來...
If this door should fall down...
或者有什麼意外...
or anything else...
這是我們巴爾的摩辦公室的電話號碼
this is the number for our Baltimore office.
他們知道你跟我在一起的
They know that you're with me.
-如果有意外就找他們吧　-好的，史達琳小姐
- Call them if anything should happen. - Yes, Miss Starling.
克麗絲，他們在等你
Clarice. Here, they're waiting for you.
小心
Watch your step.
「赫斯達・莫菲」是拼字猜謎吧？
Hester Mofet. It's an anagram, isn't it, doctor?
意思是「我其餘的東西」
Hester Mofet: "The rest of me"?
那表示車庫是你租的？
"Miss The Rest Of Me," meaning that you rented that garage?
謝謝
Thank you.
你止血了
Your bleeding has stopped.
怎麼...？
How did...?
沒有大礙的
It's nothing.
只是皮外傷
It's just a scratch.
萊達醫生，那瓶里的頭顱是誰的？
Dr. Lecter, whose head is in that bottle?
為什麼你不問我，關於水牛比爾的事？
Why don't you ask me about Buffalo Bill?
你知道他的事？
Do you know something about him?
如果我看過檔案可能知道的，你可以替我拿
I might if I saw the case file. You could get that for me.
談談莫菲小姐吧，你要我去找他
Let's talk about Miss Mofet. You wanted me to find him.
他的真名是班哲文・賴普，是我的前病患
His real name is Benjamin Raspail. A former patient of mine...
他的戀愛對象，有點怪異
whose romantic attachments ran to, shall we say, the exotic.
我沒有殺他，只是把他藏起來，就像我發現他時的樣子
I did not kill him, merely tucked him away, very much as I found him...
在他錯過了三次約會之後
after he'd missed three appointments.
若你沒有殺他，那麼是誰殺？
If you didn't kill him, who did?
誰知道？對他來說是件好事
Who can say? Best thing for him, really.
他的治療沒有功效
His therapy was going nowhere.
他的裙子，化妝...
His dress, makeup...
賴普是個異性裝扮癖好者？
Raspail was a transvestite?
生活上？不是，只是普通的躁狂抑鬱
In life? Oh, no. Garden variety manic-depressive.
乏味，非常乏味
Tedious, very tedious.
現在我把他看成是一個實驗
I now think of him as an experiment.
一個沒經驗的殺手嘗試轉變
A fledgling killer's first effort at transformation.
你看到他時有何感覺？
How did you feel when you saw him, Clarice?
初時很害怕，後來...
Scared at first, then...
便很振奮
exhilarated.
克勞福在提拔你，是嗎？
Jack Crawford is helping your career, isn't he?
看來你們互相傾慕呢
Apparently, he likes you and you like him too.
我從沒有想過
I never thought about it.
你認為克勞福對你有遐想嗎？
Do you think Jack Crawford wants you, sexually?
他年紀大很多，你對他可有想入非非？
He is much older, but do you think he visualizes scenarios, exchanges?
跟你做愛？
Fucking you?
我沒有興趣，這是邁克斯會說的那種話
That doesn't interest me. It's the sort of thing that Miggs would say.
不再是了
Not anymore.
謝謝你，巴尼
Thank you, Barney.
你的畫呢？
What happened to your drawings?
懲罰，為了邁克斯那件事，像那個傳道節目...
Punishment, you see, for Miggs. Just like that gospel program.
你離開後他們就會調高聲音
When you leave, they'll turn the volume way up.
奇頓醫生喜歡這些折磨伎倆
Dr. Chilton does enjoy his petty torments.
你說轉變是什麼意思？
What did you mean by "transformation," doctor?
克麗絲，我在這裡八年了
I've been in this room for eight years now, Clarice.
我知道在我有生之年，他們都不會釋放我
I know they will never ever let me out while I'm alive.
我想要的是一個景觀
What I want is a view.
我想要一個看到樹和水的窗戶
I want a window where I can see a tree or even water.
我想去一間遠離奇頓醫生的聯邦監獄
I want to be in a federal institution far away from Dr. Chilton.
你說「沒經驗的殺手」，是什麼意思？
What did you mean by "fledgling killer"?
你是否說他已經再次殺人？
Are you saying he's killed again?
我根據案件的證據，給你對水牛比爾...
I'm offering you a psychological profile on Buffalo Bill...
作心理分析
based on the case evidence.
我會幫你抓到他
I'll help you catch him, Clarice.
你知道他是誰，是不是？
You know who he is, don't you?
告訴我誰把你的病人斬首了
Tell me who decapitated your patient, doctor.
願意等待的人都有好報的
All good things to those who wait.
我已經等了，但傑克能等多久？
I've waited, Clarice. But how long can you and old Jackie-boy wait?
我們的小比爾一定正在找尋著，下一位特別的女士了
Our little Billy must already be searching for that next special lady.
（田納西州孟斐斯市）
小貓咪
Hey, little cheeper.
我快來了
I'll be right there.
天啊！
Jeez!
要我幫忙嗎？
Can I help you with that?
可以嗎？
Would you?
當然可以
Sure.
謝謝你
Thank you.
不用客氣，你好像是傷殘人士
That's all right. You look kind of handicapped.
是的，我搬到這裡但搬不上貨車
Yeah. I got it this far, I just can't get it up in the truck by myself.
來吧，抓著，上！
Here, grab this. Up!
好的
Okay.
把它放下吧，很好
Just set it down. That's good.
你上車，我想把它推進去
Get in the truck. I want to push it all the way up.
真的很謝謝你
I really appreciate this. Thank you.
放到後面去
Just go all the way back.
行了嗎？
Okay. Is this good?
行了，很好
Yeah, that's good.
-真好　-好的
- That's great. - Okay.
你大概穿十四號吧？
Say, are you about a size 14?
什麼？
Sorry?
（十四號）
好
Good.
好極了...
Oh, good. Good.
抓著
Holds!
一！
Ones!
史達琳！
Starling!
出去，我們走吧
Outside. Let's go.
仙蒂，進場代替史達琳，來吧
Cindy, in the ring for Starling. Let's go!
收拾你的裝備
Pack your field gear.
-我們會跟克勞福一起去　-去哪裡？
- You're going with Crawford. - Where?
在西維吉尼亞，發現了一名女子屍體
Found a girl's body in West Virginia.
她在水里一周了，看來是水牛比爾做的
Been in the water a week. Looks like Buffalo Bill.
（西維吉尼亞州克萊縣）
（聯邦調查局）
讓她們活上三天，我們不明白原因
Keeps them alive for three days. We don't know why.
死前沒有強姦或虐待的跡象
No evidence of rape or physical abuse prior to death.
這些傷口都是死後造成的
All the mutilation you see there is postmortem.
三天...
Okay, three days...
然後他開槍射死她們，剝皮和棄屍
then he shoots them, skins them and dumps them
每個屍體棄置在不同的河上
Each body in a different river.
河水衝走了證據
The water leaves us no trace evidence of any kind.
那是第一個，費迪嘉・拜姆
That's Fredrica Bimmel, the first one.
她的屍體是唯一被他沈下去的
Her body was the only one he weighted down.
實際上，她是第三個被發現的
So actually, she was the third girl found.
繼她之後，他變得懶惰了
After her, he got lazy.
好的，我們看看
Okay, let's see.
圓圈是那些女子被擄走的位置，箭嘴是屍體被發現的地點
Circles where the girls were abducted. Arrows where their bodies were found.
今天這個被衝到這裡來，在西維吉尼亞州埃爾克河被發現
This new one today washed up here. Elk River, West Virginia.
史達琳，仔細看看，告訴我你有什麼發現
Look at him, Starling. Tell me what you see.
他是個白種男人
Well, he's a white male.
連環殺手傾向於在自己的族群中獵殺
Serial killers tend to hunt within their own ethnic groups.
他不是個流浪者，他有自己的獨立房子
He's not a drifter. He's got his own house, not an apartment.
-為什麼？　-他下毒手時，需要私人地方
- Why? - What he does with them takes privacy.
他年約三四十歲，孔武有力
He's in his 30s or 40s. He's got real physical strength.
還有中年人的自制能力，謹慎而準繩
Combined with an older man's self-control. He's cautious, precise.
他從來不衝動，也不會罷休
And he's never impulsive. He'll never stop.
為什麼
Why not?
他已經迷上了這回事，而且越來越熟練
He's got a real taste for it now, and he's getting better at his work.
不錯呢，有問題嗎？
Not bad, Starling. Questions?
有的
Yes, sir.
你沒有提及我報告里的任何資料
You haven't mentioned anything about the information in my report...
或者萊達醫生的提議
or Dr. Lecter's offer, sir.
我正在考慮中
I'm considering it.
所以你派我去病院
That's why you sent me in there, isn't it?
找他協助緝捕水牛比爾？
To get his help on Buffalo Bill, sir?
如果那是事實...
Well, if that was the case, then I just...
我希望可以早點知道罷了
I just wish I was in on it, that's all.
若以真正目的派你去，萊達會識破的
If I'd sent you in there with a real agenda, Lecter would have known it.
他會把你玩弄，什麼也不會說
He would have toyed with you, then turned to stone.
（格里殯儀館）
打擾了，柏金斯警長？
Excuse me, Sheriff Perkins?
這些是聯邦調查局人員
These are the FBI people.
柏金斯警長，我是傑克・克勞福，這是泰瑞和史達琳
Sheriff Perkins, Jack Crawford, FBI. Special Agent Terry, Agent Starling.
感謝邀請我們來到你們的管轄區
We appreciate being invited to your jurisdiction.
是州政府檢察部找你們的
Somebody from the state attorney's office called you.
我們會通力合作，但現在...
We'll extend you every courtesy, but right now...
警長
Sheriff...
我認為該在私底下談論這類性罪行的細節
this type of sex crime has aspects I'd just as soon discuss in private.
你明白吧？
Know what I mean?
奧加，去教堂叫區醫生來
Oscar, fetch Dr. Akin from the chapel.
我們在後面這裡
We're back here.
叫拉瑪彈奏完畢後過來
Tell Lamar to come on when he's finished playing his music.
是的，我們稍後會傳過來
Yeah, we'll be sending in a minute.
行了
It's working.
我要組成六線聯繫，芝加哥，底特律...
I need a six-way link up. Chicago, Detroit...
什麼？
What? What?
對不起
Excuse me.
對不起，各位警官先生，聽著
Excuse me, officers and gentlemen. Listen here, now.
我們要替她做一些事情
There's things we need to do for her.
你們把她帶來了這裡，她的家人會感謝...
Y'all brought her this far, and her folks would thank you if they could...
你們的善意和體諒
for your kindness and your sensitivity.
請離開吧，讓我們照顧她好了
Please, go on now, and let us take care of her.
走吧
Go on, now.
謝謝
Thank you.
很好
Okay, good.
是的，埃爾克河，準備傳送
Yeah, that's right. Elk River. Stand by for transmission.
瑞
Ray.
大家來看看她吧
Doctor, Lamar. Let's take a look at her.
天啊
Jesus...
史達琳，行了
Okay, Starling.
胸骨上有星形的傷口
Star-shaped contact entrance wound over the sternum.
上面有個槍口印記
A muzzle stamp at the top.
-死於非命　-死於非命
- Wrongful death. - Wrongful death.
她要被送去克拉斯頓的病理學家那裡
She'll have to go to the state pathologist's at Claxton.
我還是回去那個喪禮了
Well, I better get back to that service.
利瑪會幫你們的
Lamar will help you.
老天爺
Lord Almighty.
你還觀察到什麼？
What else do you see, Starling?
她不是當地人
Well, she's not local.
她穿了三個耳洞，還有...
Her ears are pierced three times and there's...
閃亮的指甲油，看來是城市人
glitter nail polish. It looks like town to me.
她有兩只指甲斷了
Two of her fingernails are broken off...
指甲下有泥土和沙粒
and there's dirt or grit under them.
她好像想爬過一些什麼似的
It looks like she's tried to claw her way through something.
瑞，替她的牙齒拍照，稍後傳真到失蹤人口組
Ray, get pictures of her teeth. We'll fax them to Missing Persons.
好的
Right.
再拍一張
Let's do another.
她喉嚨里有東西
She's got something in her throat.
當屍體被撈出水面時
When a body comes out of the water...
口裡總會有些樹葉之類的東西
lots of times there's leaves and things in the mouth.
那是什麼？
What is that?
豆莢嗎？
Some kind of seedpod?
不，是一隻蟲繭
No, sir. That's a bug cocoon.
沒可能自己走進去的
There's no way that could get way down in there.
除非有人把它塞進去
Not unless somebody shoved it in there.
我們把她翻過來會較易採指紋
She'll be easier to print when we turn her.
幫幫我
Lamar, give me a hand?
好的
Yes, sir, I will.
你看這些是什麼？
Oh, Jack. What do you make of these?
跟其他死者的形狀不同，拍幾張大特寫
Different configuration than the other victims. Get close-ups.
死者的皮膚...
Victim's skin removed...
在臀部以上，有兩塊菱形的皮膚被剝去
in two diamond-shaped sections above the buttocks.
傷口跟第二或第三節脊骨平衡
Exit wound level with the second or third thoracic vertebrae...
距離右肩胛骨大約六英吋
approximately six inches from the right shoulder blade.
史達琳
Starling...
我對那個警長說，我們不該在女人面前談
when I told that sheriff we shouldn't talk in front of a woman...
那令你很氣惱吧？
that burned you, didn't it?
那只是個煙幕，我要打發他走
It was just smoke, Starling. I had to get rid of him
是很要緊
It matters, Mr. Crawford.
探員們想看你怎樣應付
Cops look at you to see how to act.
很要緊的
It matters.
我明白了
Point taken.
手腕周圍有被捆綁的痕跡
Ligature marks found around wrists...
足踝就沒有
not around the ankles.
顯示死後才剝皮的
This would indicate that the skinning was postmortem.
時間到了，輪到我
Time, Pilch. My move.
-不公平，你用食物引誘它　-真無賴，仍然是輪到我
- No fair! You lured him with produce. - Tough noogies. It's still my turn.
寶貝，慢慢來
Nice and slow, baby.
若那只甲蟲推動你的棋子，也算數嗎？
If the beetle moves one of your men, does that still count?
當然算數，你怎麼玩的？
Of course it counts. How do you play?
史達琳探員？
Agent Starling?
這東西從哪裡來的？
Where the heck did this come from?
它粘糊糊的
It's practically mush.
在一個被殺死者身上找到的，屍體在埃爾克河裡
It was found in a murder victim. The body was in the Elk River.
是水牛比爾乾的嗎？
It's Buffalo Bill, isn't it?
我不能透露
I can't tell you any more.
我們在電台聽到
We heard it on the radio.
這是一宗真實謀殺案的線索？酷
You mean this is a clue from a real murder case? Cool!
別管他，他是無名小卒
Just ignore him. He's not a Ph.D.
小角天蛾，可能是...
Sphingid Ceratomia, maybe...
它是只大吸血鬼
Boy, he's a big sucker.
好吧
Okay...
查看一下形態學
let's check morphology.
史達琳探員，你不查案時會做什麼？
What do you do when you're not detecting, Agent Starling?
做個學生
Try to be a student, Dr. Pilcher.
你去過吃起司漢堡和喝啤酒嗎？
You ever go out for cheeseburgers and beer?
那有趣的招牌酒？
The amusing house wine?
博士，你是否對我有意？
Are you hitting on me, doctor?
-是的　-找到了！
- Yes. - Gotcha!
你找到什麼？
What do you got?
史達琳探員，這個是陰間冥河
Agent Starling, meet Mr. Acherontia Styx.
真奇怪
Weird.
認識它的人多叫它做骷髏飛蛾
Better known to his friends as the Death's-head moth.
它從哪裡來的？
Where does it come from?
這正是古怪之處，它們只活在亞洲
That's what's strange. They only live in Asia.
它們是從進口的卵子繁殖的
They're specially raised from imported eggs.
有人飼養這只東西，餵它吃蜜糖和茄類植物
Somebody grew this guy. Fed him honey and nightshade.
給它保暖
Kept him warm.
有人很愛護它
Somebody loved him.
你在哪裡？
Where are you?!
放我出去！
Let me out of here!
餵！
Hey!
救我！
Please help me!
求你救我
Help me, please!
乾嘛你不答我？求求你！
Why won't you answer me?! Please!
-各位早，我是唐娜・佛魯茲　-我是報導體育的金・凱素
- Good morning. I'm Donna Ferucchi. - I'm Gene Cassel with sports.
我是提姆・蘭漢，今早的頭條新聞如下
And I'm Tim Langhorn. Our top story this morning:
馬丁參議員的25歲女兒凱瑟琳・馬丁...
Catherine Martin, the 25-year-old daughter of Senator Ruth Martin...
一度被列為失蹤人士
listed as a missing person...
相信她已經被稱為「水牛比爾」的殺手綁架
is believed to have been kidnapped by the killer known as "Buffalo Bill."
孟斐斯市警方說，已確認出該名失蹤女孩的襯衫
Memphis police say the missing girl's blouse has been identified...
它後面被割破，案情耐人尋味
sliced up the back, in what has become a kind of grim calling card.
凱瑟琳是田納西州的共和黨...
Young Catherine is the only daughter of U.S. Senator Ruth Martin...
馬丁參議員的獨生女
the Republican senator from Tennessee.
雖然這宗綁架案沒有政治動機
And while her kidnapping is not considered politically motivated...
但政府高層仍然相當重視
it has stirred the government to its highest levels.
正在佛蒙特州滑雪的總統
Reached for comment on the ski slopes of Vermont...
接受訪問時表示，「極度關注」事件
the president himself said to be, and I quote, "intensely concerned."
馬丁參議員於較早前，錄影了以下的呼籲
Just moments ago, Senator Martin taped this dramatic personal plea:
我向挾持小女的人說話
I'm speaking, now, to the person holding my daughter.
凱瑟琳是非常溫文和善良的
Catherine is very gentle and kind.
你跟她談談就知道
Talk to her and you'll see.
你有力量，你有控制權
You have the power. You are in charge.
我知道你感受到愛和善心的
I know you can feel love and compassion.
你有一個向全世界展示的大好機會...
You have a wonderful chance to show the whole world...
就是你是善良而堅強的
that you can be merciful, as well as strong.
你有能力善待凱瑟琳...
That you're big enough to treat Catherine better...
比這個世界待你更好
than the world has treated you.
你有此能力
You have that power.
求你，我的女兒是凱瑟琳
Please. My daughter is Catherine.
真是聰明
Boy, that's smart.
真的很聰明
Jesus, that's really smart.
她不斷重復那個名字
She keeps repeating the name.
若他視凱瑟琳為一個人而非物件，就難以下毒手
If he sees Catherine as a person, not an object, it's harder to tear her up.
求你放了我的女兒
Please, release my little girl.
史達琳小姐，你來我的醫院幹什麼？
What you're doing, Ms. Starling, is coming into my hospital...
並第三次拒絕跟我分享資料
and refusing to share information with me for the third time.
這不過是賴普案的例行後續
Sir, I told you this is just a routine follow-up on the Raspail...
他是我的病人，我有知情權
He is my patient. I have rights.
我明白
I understand that.
史達琳小姐，我不是個笨蛋
Look, I am not just some turnkey, Miss Starling.
這是檢察官的電話號碼
This is the number for the U.S. Attorney.
請你跟他談，或者讓我執行任務，明白嗎？
Please, either discuss it with him or let me do my job, you understand?
如果你的分析能幫助我們抓到水牛比爾...
If your profile helps us catch Buffalo Bill...
及時救出凱瑟琳・馬丁...
in time to save Catherine Martin...
參議員答應把你轉送到...
the senator promises you a transfer to the VA Hospital...
它位於紐約奧尼達公園，可看到附近的園林景色的醫院
at Oneida Park, New York, with a view of the woods nearby.
當然仍是高度設防的
Maximum security still applies, of course.
你可以閱讀書籍
You'd have reasonable access to books.
最好的是...
Best of all, though...
你每年可以離開醫院一周
one week of the year, you get to leave the hospital...
去這裡
and go here:
普拉姆島
Plum Island.
在那一星期里，你都可以在沙灘漫步
Every day of that week, you may walk on the beach
也可以在海中暢泳一小時
You may swim in the ocean for up to one hour...
當然是受特種部隊的監視
under SWAT team surveillance, of course.
給你的
And there you have it.
水牛比爾的檔案副本
A copy of the Buffalo Bill case file.
參議員的建議書副本
A copy of the senator's offer.
這個建議是無商討餘地的
This offer is non-negotiable and final.
凱瑟琳・馬丁死了你就一無所得
Catherine Martin dies, you get nothing.
普拉姆島動物病症研究中心
Plum Island Animal Disease Research Center.
聽來很吸引
Sounds charming.
那個島有一流的海灘
That's only part of the island. There's a very nice beach.
島上有燕鷗巢，有漂亮的...
Terns nest there. There's beautiful...
燕鷗？
Terns?
如果我幫你，也會是我們的轉機
If I help you, Clarice, it will be "turns" with us too.
我們互相交換資料吧
Quid pro quo. I tell you things, you tell me things.
但不是關於這宗案件，是關於你自己
Not about this case, though. About yourself.
交換，好不好？
Quid pro quo. Yes or no?
好嗎？克麗絲，可憐的凱瑟琳在等著
Yes or no, Clarice? Poor little Catherine is waiting.
好吧
Go, doctor.
你最糟的童年記憶是什麼？
What is your worst memory of childhood?
家父去世
The death of my father.
告訴我，別說謊，我會知道的
Tell me about it. And don't lie, or I'll know.
他是鎮上的警長
He was a town marshal...
有一晚他遇上兩個，從藥房走出來的竊匪
and one night he surprised two burglars coming out of a drugstore.
他們向他開槍
They shot him.
他當場死亡？
Was he killed outright?
不是，他很堅強，熬了個幾個月
No, he was very strong. He lasted more than a month.
我母親在我年幼時去世
My mother died when I was very young, so...
自始父親就成為我的一切
my father had become the whole world to me...
他離開後，我一無所有，我那時十歲
and when he left me, I had nothing. I was 10 years old.
你很坦白
You're very frank, Clarice.
我相信私底下結識你，會很有意思的
I think it would be quite something to know you in private life.
交換資料
Quid pro quo, doctor.
談談西維州小姐吧，她是否身材肥大？
So tell me about Miss West Virginia. Was she a large girl?
是的
Yes.
大屁股，肉團團？
Big through the hips, roomy?
死者們全都是
They all were.
還有什麼線索？
What else?
她的喉嚨被異物塞住
She had an object deliberately inserted into her throat.
還沒有正式公佈的，我們不知道它有何意思
Now, that hasn't been made public yet. We don't know what it means.
一隻蝴蝶？
Was it a butterfly?
是的，一隻飛蛾
Yes. A moth.
一小時前，我們在班哲文・賴普的頭顱內也找到
Just like the one we found in Benjamin Raspail's head an hour ago.
為何他把它們放進去？
Why does he place them there, doctor?
飛蛾的特點是轉變
The significance of the moth is change.
幼蟲變成蝶蛹或者蛹
Caterpillar into chrysalis, or pupa...
再變成美麗的蝴蝶
and from thence into beauty.
比爾也想轉變
Our Billy wants to change too.
變性癖和暴力之間是沒有關連的
There's no correlation between transsexualism and violence.
-變性癖者是很被動的　-很聰明
- Transsexuals are very passive. - Clever girl.
你有捉拿到他的本領，知道嗎？
You're so close to the way you're gonna catch him. Do you realize that?
不知道，為什麼？
No. Tell me why.
你父親被殺後你成了孤兒，後來怎麼樣？
After your father's murder you were orphaned. What happened next?
答案並非在那雙廉價鞋子上
I don't imagine the answer is on those second-rate shoes, Clarice.
我去了蒙大拿州，跟我母親的表妹夫婦同住
I went to live with my mother's cousin and her husband in Montana.
他們有一個牧場
They had a ranch.
牧牛場？
Was it a cattle ranch?
牧羊和馬
Sheep and horses.
你在那裡住了多久？
How long did you live there?
兩個月
Two months.
為何時間這麼短？
Why so briefly?
我跑掉了
I ran away.
為什麼？牧場主人逼你口交？
Why, Clarice? Did the rancher make you perform fellatio?
他有沒有雞姦你？
Did he sodomize you?
沒有，他是個很正派的人
No. He was a very decent man.
交換資料
Quid pro quo, doctor.
比爾不是個真正的變性癖者
Billy is not a real transsexual.
但他以為自己是，他想那樣
But he thinks he is. He tries to be.
我相信他想做很多東西
He's tried to be a lot of things, I expect.
你說我有捉拿他的本領，是何意思？
You said I was very close to the way we'd catch him. What did you mean?
有三間主要做變性手術的中心
There are three major centers for transsexual surgery:
約翰・霍金斯，明尼蘇達州大學，和哥倫布醫療中心
Johns Hopkins, the University of Minnesota, and Columbus Medical Center.
若比爾向它們申請做變性手術，而又被拒絕...
I wouldn't be surprised if Billy applied for sex reassignment...
我也不會感到驚訝
at one or all of them, and been rejected.
他們根據什麼來拒絕他？
On what basis would they reject him?
試找尋跟暴力有關的童年創傷吧
Look for severe childhood disturbances associated with violence.
比爾並非天生是個罪犯
Our Billy wasn't born a criminal, Clarice...
是經過多年來慣常的，虐待所導致的
he was made one through years of systematic abuse.
他討厭自己的身份
Billy hates his own identity, you see...
他以為那是令他成為變性癖者的原因
and he thinks that makes him a transsexual...
但他的病徵要更凶殘...
but his pathology is a thousand times more savage...
和可怕千倍
and more terrifying.
它塗潤膚液在身上，它聽到指示總會依著做
It rubs the lotion on its skin. It does this whenever it's told.
先生，我的家人會付錢的
Mister, my family will pay cash.
無論你要多少贖金，他們都會付
Whatever ransom you're asking for, they'll pay it.
它塗潤膚液在身上，否則又要挨打了
It rubs the lotion on its skin or else it gets the hose again.
是的，珍寶，她會挨打的
Yes, she will, Precious. She'll get the hose.
好吧...
Okay, okay, okay.
我做吧
Okay, I'll do it.
好的
Okay.
先生，如果你放我走，我答應不會起訴你
Mister, if you let me go, I won't press charges. I promise.
我媽是個重要人物
See, my mom is a real important woman.
相信你也知道吧
I guess you already know that.
它把潤膚液放在籃里
Now it places the lotion in the basket.
求求你！
Please!
求求你，我想回家
Please, I want to go home.
我想回家！求求你！放我吧
I want to go home! Please! Please let me.
把潤膚液放在籃里
It places the lotion in the basket.
我想見我媽媽，求你放我吧
I want to see my mommy. Please let me.
我想再見到我媽媽，我想...
I want to see my mom again. I want...
我想見我媽媽
I want to see my mom.
把那他媽的潤膚液放在籃里！
Put the fucking lotion in the basket!
你仍然以為可在沙灘漫步，和看鳥兒嗎？
You still think you're gonna walk on some beach and see the birdies?
不會了
I don't think so.
我找過凱瑟琳・馬丁參議員
I called Senator Ruth Martin.
她沒聽過跟你有任何協議
She never heard of any deal with you.
他們騙你
They scammed you, Hannibal.
出去
Stand outside.
把門關上
And shut the door.
巴尼
Barney.
從沒有跟馬丁參議員作過協議，但現在有了
There never was a deal with Senator Martin, but there is now.
是我議定的
I designed it.
當然，我也為自己的利益，定下了一些條件
Of course, I worked in a few conditions for my own benefit as well.
說出水牛比爾的名字
Identify Buffalo Bill by name...
如果那個女孩及時被發現
and if the girl is found in time...
你就會被轉送到田納西州的叢樹山州立監獄
you'll be transferred to Brushy Mountain State Prison in Tennessee.
回答我
Answer me, Hannibal.
你現在回答我
You answer me now...
否則，天啊，你休想離開這個牢房
or, by God, you'll never leave this cell.
水牛比爾是誰？
Who is Buffalo Bill?
他的名字是路易斯
His first name is Louis.
其餘的我只會在田納西州，親自對參議員說
I'll tell the rest to the Senator herself, but only in Tennessee.
我也有幾個條件
And I have a few conditions of my own.
替他梳洗一下，準備出發
Clean him up and get him ready to go.
傑克，漢尼拔・萊達正被轉送往孟斐斯途中
Jack, Hannibal Lecter is being transferred to Memphis.
轉送？
Transferred?
你可有個見習生，冒參議員之名，向萊達提出一個虛假的建議？
Did you have a trainee make a phony offer to Lecter in the senator's name?
是我的主意，我逼不得已
I rolled the dice. I had to.
她氣瘋了
Well, she's mad as hell, Jack.
司法部的保羅・肯度拿來了
Paul Krendler's here from Justice.
她要求他在孟斐斯接手
She's asking him to take over in Memphis.
（孟斐斯市國際機場）
萊達醫生，歡迎到孟斐斯
Welcome to Memphis, Dr. Lecter.
我是鮑爾探員，這位是派屈克警長
I'm Lieutenant Boyle. This is Sergeant Patrick.
我們會像你待我們那麼好的
We'll treat you as good as you treat us.
你乖乖的，就會得到舒服的待遇
You be a gentleman, you'll get three hots and a cot.
長官，請在這裡簽名，我們作合法的移交
Sir, if you sign right here, we'll have us a legal transfer.
用我的吧
Here, sir, use mine.
馬丁參議員
Senator Martin...
漢尼拔・萊達醫生
Dr. Hannibal Lecter.
萊達醫生
Dr. Lecter...
我帶了一份宣誓書，保證你新的權利
l've brought an affidavit guaranteeing your new rights.
在我簽署前你要看看的
You'll want to read it before I sign.
我不會為了小利益，而耽誤你或凱瑟琳的時間
I won't waste your time or Catherine's time bargaining for petty privileges.
克麗絲・史達琳和克勞福，已經浪費了太多時間
Clarice Starling and Jack Crawford have wasted too much time already.
但願他們沒有害死，那個可憐的女孩
I only pray they haven't doomed the poor girl.
讓我幫你吧，事成後我會信任你
Let me help you now. I will trust you when it is all over.
我答應你，保羅
You have my word. Paul.
水牛比爾的真名是路易斯・法蘭
Buffalo Bill's real name is Louis Friend.
我只見過他一次，1980年4 5月間由我的病人...
I met him just once. He was referred to me in April or May, 1980...
班哲文・賴普轉介給我的
by my patient Benjamin Raspail.
他們是愛人
They were lovers, you see.
但賴普變得很害怕
But Raspail had become very frightened.
看來路易斯謀殺了一個流浪漢
Apparently, Louis had murdered a transient...
用他的皮膚做了一些東西
and done things with the skin.
我們要他的地址和容貌特徵
We need his address and a physical description.
告訴我，參議員...
Tell me, senator.
你有沒有親自哺育凱瑟琳？
Did you nurse Catherine yourself?
-什麼？　-你有沒有給她餵奶？
- What? - Did you breast-feed her?
-混帳　-我有的
- Now, wait a minute! - Yes. I did.
令你的乳頭變得堅挺，是嗎？
Toughened your nipples, didn't it?
你這個混蛋！
You son of a bitch!
把人的腿切除，他仍感到振奮
Amputate a man's leg, and he can still feel it tickling.
告訴我，媽媽，當你的小女兒被殺時
Tell me, Mom, when your little girl is on the slab...
你哪裡會感到振奮？
where will it tickle you?
把這個畜生帶回巴爾的摩
Take this thing back to Baltimore.
五英尺十英吋，身材魁悟，約一百八十磅
Five-foot-ten, strongly built, about 180 pounds.
金髮，淺藍色眼睛
Hair, blond. Eyes, pale blue.
他現在大約三十五歲
He'd be about 35 now.
他聲稱住在費城，可能是說謊
He said he lived in Philadelphia but may have lied.
我只記得這麼多了，媽
That's all I can remember, Mom.
若我再想起什麼，我會通知你的
But if I think of any more, I will let you know.
參議員，還有一件事
Oh, and senator, just one more thing:
你的套裝很漂亮
Love your suit.
與馬丁參議員，在今天較早前的會面中
In a meeting earlier today with Senator Ruth Martin...
萊達醫生同意協助追緝水牛比爾
Dr. Lecter agreed to help in the investigation to find Buffalo Bill.
（謝爾比縣法院大樓）
-你扮演什麼角色？　-我對萊達醫生的...
- How do you fit in? - My unique insight...
獨特觸覺促成了這次突破
into Lecter made the breakthrough.
水牛比爾叫什麼名字？
Buffalo Bill's name?
這是目前有關當局的秘密
His name is now a matter of record with the proper authorities.
-可否給我們...　-我是奇頓醫生
- Can you give us...? - I'm Dr. Frederick Chilton.
-怎樣寫法？　-奇特的奇...
- Spell it? - That's C-H...
你是奇頓醫生的組員嗎？
Are you with Dr. Chilton's group?
我剛在外面見到他
Well, I just saw him outside, sir.
不能有太多人接近萊達，我們接到死亡恐嚇
Access to Lecter is limited. We've received death threats.
我明白的
I understand, sir.
登記和把武器放下
Log in and check your weapon.
我不能獨自邀功的
I can't take all the credit myself.
馬丁參議員，司法部，聯邦調查局
Senator Martin, Justice Department, FBI...
巴爾的摩州立醫院的人員，最困難就是...
folks at the Baltimore State Hospital. Now for the hard part:
逮捕那個疑匪
Apprehending the suspect.
對不起，我要趕飛機了
Excuse me, I have to catch a flight.
指揮台，我是傑各警員
Command desk, Officer Jacobs.
（路易斯・法蘭飛禽，猥褻）
（鐵）
-他們說的是事實嗎？　-什麼？
- Is it true what they're saying? - Huh?
他是個吸血殭屍？
He's some kind of vampire?
他們沒有替他取名
They don't have a name for what he is.
小姐，你知道規矩的吧？
You do know the rules, ma'am?
知道，我以前盤問過他
Yes, I've questioned him before.
去吧
Go ahead.
克麗絲，晚安
Good evening, Clarice.
你可能想要回你的畫吧
I thought you might like your drawings back.
直到你有自己的景觀
Just until you get your view.
真是周到
How very thoughtful.
還是在你們破案前，克勞福派你來...
Or did Jack Crawford send you for one last wheedle...
說最後一次的花言巧語？
before you're both booted off the case?
不，是我自己想來的
No. I came because I wanted to.
人家會說我們在戀愛呢
People will say we're in love.
安克斯島
Anthrax Island.
真是有心思，克麗絲
That was an especially nice touch, Clarice.
你畫的？
Yours?
是
Yes.
對
Yeah.
很好
That was good.
但我同情可憐的凱瑟琳
Pity about poor Catherine, though.
滴答...
Ticktock, ticktock, ticktock.
你的字謎有破綻了
Your anagrams are showing, doctor.
路易斯・法蘭？
Louis Friend?
是硫化鐵，也叫做黃銅鐵
Iron sulfide, also known as fool's gold.
克麗絲，你的毛病是，你要活得輕鬆一點
Oh, Clarice, your problem is, you need to get more fun out of life.
你在巴爾的摩時說了真話
You were telling me the truth back in Baltimore, sir.
現在繼續吧
Please continue now.
我看過那些檔案了，你看過嗎？
Well, I've read the case files. Have you?
你要緝拿他的資料都在裡面
Everything you need to find him is there in those pages.
-那麼教我怎樣做　-首要的原則
- Then tell me how. - First principles, Clarice.
是簡易，讀馬可・奧勒利烏斯吧
Simplicity. Read Marcus Aurelius.
凡事都問：它是什麼？
Of each particular thing, ask: What is it in itself?
它有什麼本質？
What is its nature?
你尋找的這個人，他做什麼？
What does he do, this man you seek?
殺害女人
He kills women.
不，那是次要的
No. That is incidental.
他主要是做什麼？他殺人是為了滿足什麼？
What is the principle thing he does? What needs does he serve by killing?
憤怒
Anger...
社會認同和性困惑
social acceptance and sexual frustration...
不是！
No!
他貪圖
He covets.
那是他的本性
That is his nature.
我們怎樣才會開始貪圖？
And how do we begin to covet, Clarice?
我們是否去尋找貪圖的東西？
Do we seek out things to covet?
嘗試回答吧
Make an effort to answer now.
不是，我們只是...
No, we just...
我們看見日常的東西就開始貪圖
No, we begin by coveting what we see every day.
你可有感到一些眼睛在盯著你？
Don't you feel eyes moving over your body, Clarice?
你的眼睛，又可有尋找你要的東西？
And don't your eyes seek out the things you want?
有的，請你告訴我吧
All right, yes. Now, please tell me how.
不
No.
輪到你告訴我了
It is your turn to tell me, Clarice.
你再沒有假期可哄騙我了
You don't have any more vacations to sell.
為何你離開那個牧場？
Why did you leave that ranch?
我們沒有時間再玩這一套了
Doctor, we don't have any more time for any of this now.
但我們的時間觀念是不同的
But we don't reckon time the same way, do we?
你只有這麼多的時間
This is all the time you'll have.
稍後吧，請聽著，我們只有五個...
Later. Please listen. We've only got five...
不，我現在要聽
No! I will listen now.
父親被殺後，你十歲就成了孤兒
Your father's murder orphaned you when you were 10.
你去了蒙大拿，跟一些養羊馬的表親同住，之後呢？
You went to live with cousins on a sheep and horse ranch in Montana. And?
我在一個早上跑掉了
And one morning I just ran away.
不是的，什麼驅使你離開？
Not "just," Clarice. What set you off?
你在什麼時候出發？
You started at what time?
很早，天還沒亮
Early, still dark.
有東西吵醒你，是不是一個夢？
Then something woke you. Was it a dream?
是什麼？
What was it?
我聽到一種奇怪的聲音
I heard a strange noise.
是什麼？
What was it?
是...
It was...
尖叫聲
screaming.
像小孩的尖叫聲
Some kind of screaming, like a child's voice.
你怎麼做？
What did you do?
我下樓
I went...
走出屋外
downstairs. Outside.
我偷進了殼倉
I crept up into the barn.
我很害怕看進去，但又必須看
I was so scared to look inside, but I had to.
你看見什麼？克麗絲？
And what did you see, Clarice? What did you see?
一些羔羊
Lambs.
它們在尖叫
They were screaming.
他們在宰殺那些羔羊？
They were slaughtering the spring lambs?
而它們在尖叫
And they were screaming.
那你就跑掉了？
And you ran away?
不是，最初我想釋放它們
No. First I tried to free them.
我打開它們的閘門
I opened the gate to their pen.
它們只是站在那裡，很困惑的，不肯走
They just stood there, confused. They wouldn't run.
但你可以走，你也走了，是不是？
But you could and you did, didn't you?
是的，我抱起一隻羊就拔足逃跑
Yes. I took one lamb and I ran away as fast as I could.
你去哪裡？
Where were you going, Clarice?
不知道，我沒有食物和水
I don't know. I didn't have any food, any water...
而且當時很冷，非常冷
and it was very cold. It was very cold.
我以為...
I thought...
我以為，至少可救到一隻羊
I thought if I could save just one...
但它很重
but he was so heavy.
真的很重
He was so heavy.
我走不了幾里路，警長的車就把我截住
I didn't get more than a few miles when the sheriffs car picked me up.
牧場主人很生氣，把我送到博斯曼的路德會孤兒院
The rancher was so angry he sent me to a Lutheran orphanage in Bozeman.
我再沒看過那個牧場了
I never saw the ranch again.
你的羊又怎麼樣？
What became of your lamb, Clarice?
他們把它殺了
They killed him.
有時你仍會驚醒，是嗎？
You still wake up sometimes, don't you?
在黑暗中醒來...
Wake up in the dark...
聽到那些羔羊的尖叫聲？
and hear the screaming of the lambs?
是的
Yes.
你相信如果把凱瑟琳救了出來
And you think if you save poor Catherine...
可以令它們停止尖叫是嗎？你相信如果凱瑟琳活著...
you can make them stop, don't you? You think if Catherine lives...
你就不會在黑夜中...
you won't wake up in the dark ever again...
再被那些恐怖的羊聲驚醒了
to that awful screaming of the lambs.
我不知道
I don't know.
謝謝你，克麗絲
Thank you, Clarice.
謝謝你
Thank you.
告訴我他的名字
Tell me his name, doctor.
是奇頓醫生吧
Dr. Chilton, I presume.
我相信你們是認識的
I think you know each other.
好吧
Okay.
-我們找到她了　-我們走吧
- We found her. - Let's go.
醫生，輪到你了
It's your turn, doctor.
-出去　-說出他的名字
- Out! - Tell me his name.
抱歉，我接到命令，要把你送上飛機
Sorry, ma'am, I've got orders to put you on a plane.
走吧
Come on, now.
勇敢的克麗絲
Brave Clarice.
那些羔羊停止尖叫時，你會告訴我的，是嗎？
You will let me know when those lambs stop screaming, won't you?
說出他的名字
Tell me his name, doctor!
克麗絲
Clarice!
你的檔案
Your case file.
餵！
Hey!
再見，克麗絲
Goodbye, Clarice.
醫生，準備好就來吧
Ready when you are, doc.
請等一會
Just another minute, please.
那個混蛋竟然要再吃晚飯
Son of a bitch demanded a second dinner.
還要極生的羊排
Lamb chops, extra rare.
不知他早餐要吃什麼？動物園裡的怪物？
Wonder what he wants for breakfast? Some damn thing from the zoo?
（化學噴霧）
兩位，晚安
Good evening, gentlemen.
好的，醫生，蹲下吧
Okay, doc. Grab some floor.
跟以前的程序一樣
Same drill as before, please.
龐畢探員，準備好了
Ready when you are, Sergeant Pembry.
行了
Okay.
遞給我吧
Hand me that, would you?
謝謝
Thanks.
請小心那些畫
Mind the drawings, please.
謝謝你
Thank you.
龐畢，小心，他把我扣住
Pembry, watch it, he's cuffed me!
天啊
Jesus Christ!
龐畢探員，準備好就來吧
Ready when you are, Sergeant Pembry.
究竟什麼回事？
What is this shit?
有人上了五樓？
Did somebody go up on five?
-沒有人上過去　-叫龐畢，叫他告訴...
- No, nobody went up. - Call Pembry. Ask him to tell...
CP，五樓有槍聲，重復，五樓有槍聲
CP, shots fired on five. Repeat, shots fired on five.
戴德警官
Sergeant Tate!
去，五樓有槍聲
Proceed. Shots fired on five.
天啊！
Holy shit!
-怎麼了？　-混蛋！
- What the hell? - Bitch!
閉嘴！
Shut up!
波比，拿避彈衣來
Bobby, get the vest.
是，警官
Right, sarge.
-布萊迪，霍華，掩護　-看！
- Brady, Howard, cover... - Look!
它停了
It stopped.
封鎖方圓十幢樓的範圍
Seal off a 10-block radius.
召特種部隊和救護車來，快點！
Get me the SWAT team and an ambulance, double quick.
我們上樓去
We're going up.
龐畢？
Pembry?!
鮑爾？
Boyle?!
天啊！
Oh, God!
去
Go.
-沒有人　-沒有人
- Clear. - Clear.
指揮站
Command post.
兩個警員死了
Two officers down.
-沒有人　-沒有人
- Clear! - Clear!
警官，萊達不見了
Lecter's gone, sarge.
囚犯失蹤了
Prisoner is missing.
鮑爾的配槍不見了
Boyle's gun is gone.
重復，萊達持械失蹤了
Repeat. Lecter is missing and armed.
他拿走了床鋪
He stripped the bed.
可能用來做繩，搜查所有窗戶
Might be making a rope. Check all the windows.
救護車在哪裡？
Where the fuck is my ambulance?
他仍活著的
He's alive.
戴德警官，他仍活著！
Sergeant Tate! He's alive!
扶著他，撫摸他的手，跟他說話
Get ahold of him and feel his hands. Talk to him!
說什麼？
What do I say?
他是龐德吉姆，跟他說話，該死
It's Jim Pembry. Now talk to him, damn it!
萊達持械失蹤了
Lecter is missing and armed.
-龐畢...你聽到我嗎？　-他拿了鮑爾的配槍
- Pembry. Pembry, can you hear me? - He took Boyle's gun.
龐畢發過一槍，萊達可能中了槍的
Pembry got off one round. There's a chance Lecter's hit.
繼續呼吸吧
Keep breathing in and out.
你做得很好，你沒事的
You're doing a good job. You look real good there.
對，你沒事的
Yeah, you look... Look real good.
-準備了嗎？　-來吧
- You ready? - Let's go!
-我們來吧　-好的，走吧
- Let's do it. - Okay, let's go!
很好，你支持得住的
Looking good. You're gonna make it.
沒事的
Everything's just fine.
-我要作靜脈注射　-乳酸林格注射液
- I need that IV now! - Lactated Ringer's.
可否拿那條帶子來？氧氣在哪裡？
Can we get the strap? Where's the oxygen?
老兄，情況很好，鎮定一點
Doing good, buddy. That's right. Stay with me here.
他不行了，去樓下，快點
We're losing him! Downstairs, quickly!
抬起！
And up!
-電梯！　-這邊
- Elevator! - This way!
-讓開！　-讓開！
- Out of the way! - Get out of the way!
CP叫戴德
CP to Tate.
收到，我是戴德
Roger, lieutenant. Tate here.
我現在乘電梯送龐畢下來
I'm on the elevator bringing Pembry down.
他看來支持得住
He seems to be hanging on.
最高的三層樓封鎖了
Top three floors secured.
主要樓梯封鎖了
Main stairwell secured.
我們相信他在二樓
We think he's on two.
戴德，你聽到嗎？
Tate, you still with me?
我們頗肯定他在二樓
We're pretty sure he's somewhere on two, sir.
通話暫時完畢
That's all for now. Over.
他在電梯頂
He's on the roof of the elevator.
好的，大家來
Okay, guys.
我看到他
I see him.
他的手旁邊有一支槍，他沒有動
There's a gun by his hand. He's not moving.
-警告，我們要生擒他　-知道
- One warning. We need him alive. - Got it.
萊達？
Lecter?
把雙手放在頭上
Put your hands on your head.
向腿射一槍
One in the leg.
沒有動靜
No movement.
約翰，不要開槍，我們要進入電梯
Johnny, hold your fire. We're coming into the car.
我們會打開蓋口
We're opening the hatch.
小心他的手
Watch his hands.
如果有開火，會是我們發的，確定
If there's any fire, it'll come from us. Affirm.
明白
Got it.
孟斐斯醫院，這是26號車
Memphis General, this is Unit 26.
我們會送來一名五十歲男警
We're inbound with a 50-year-old male officer...
他面部有嚴重割傷
with severe facial lacerations.
他全身出現抽搐，情況嚴重
He had grand mal seizure activity. He's postdictal now.
-收到　-重要器官情況良好
- I copy. - Vital signs are good.
-血壓是130/90　-90？
- Pressure is 130l90. - Ninety?
對，是90，脈搏84
Yeah, that's right, 90. Pulse, 84.
我們給他注射了乳酸林格注射液
We got him on lactated Ringer's running...
病人正在吸十公升的氧氣
and the patient is on 10 liters of oxygen.
小心！
Watch it!
那輛救護車在孟斐斯機場一個車庫里被發現
The ambulance was found in a parking garage at Memphis Airport.
工作人員死了
The crew was dead.
他還殺了一名遊客
He killed a tourist too.
拿了他的衣服和鈔票
Got his clothes, cash.
他可能在任何地方
By now he could be anywhere.
-他不會來對付我的　-真的？
- He won't come after me. - Oh, really?
他不會的
He won't.
我不能解釋
I can't explain it.
他認為那樣做很無禮
He would consider that rude.
都完了，她已經死了
It's over. She's dead.
這不是你的錯
It's not your fault.
萊達說，我們需要捉拿他的資料都在這裡，但我不能...
Lecter said everything we need to catch him with is here, only I can't...
萊達醫生說了很多話
Dr. Lecter said a lot of things.
雅戴，他在這裡的
He's here, Ardelia.
這是萊達的筆跡嗎？
Is this Lecter's handwriting?
這樣雜亂地分布現場，不是有點極度隨意嗎？
"Doesn't this random scattering of sites seem desperately random?
像個差勁說謊者的精心策劃？漢尼拔・萊達
Like the elaboration of a bad liar? Ta. Hannibal Lecter."
「極度隨意」，他是什麼意思？
"Desperately random." What does he mean?
可能根本不是隨意，是有一個模式的
Not random at all, maybe. Like there's a pattern here.
但並沒有模式，不然電腦也會發現
But there's no pattern or the computers would've nailed it.
屍體甚至是不依次序被發現的
They're even found in random order.
不依次序是因為那個被他沈下的女孩
Random because of the one girl. The one he weighted down.
-費迪嘉・拜姆　-對
- Fredrica Bimmel. - Right.
來自俄亥俄州的貝爾維迪爾
From Belvedere, Ohio.
第一個遇害的女孩，屍體是第三個被發現，為什麼？
The first girl taken, third body found. Why?
她沒有漂浮，他把她沈下去
She didn't drift. He weighted her down.
萊達說的首要原則是什麼？
What did Lecter say about the "first principles"?
簡易
Simplicity.
這個傢伙做什麼？他貪圖
What does this guy do? He covets.
我們怎樣開始貪圖的？
How do we first start to covet?
我們貪圖見到的東西
We covet what we see.
每天見到的
Every day.
該死，克麗絲
Hot damn, Clarice.
他認識她的
He knew her.
（俄亥俄州貝爾維迪爾市）
貝先生？
Mr. Bimmel?
我是
That's me.
你好，我是克麗絲・史達琳，聯邦調查局探員
Hello, I'm Clarice Starling. I'm with the FBI.
貝先生，我想四周看看
I appreciate you letting me take a look around, Mr. Bimmel.
我沒有什麼新資料給你了
I don't know nothing new to tell you.
警方已經來過很多次
Police been back here so many times already.
費迪坐巴士去芝加哥求職
Fredrica went into Chicago on the bus to see about a job.
她好端端的離開面試
She left the interview okay.
就沒有回家
She never come home.
她的臥房是原封不動的
Her bedroom's how she left it.
在樓上
Upstairs.
左邊那一間
Door to the left.
他在替自己做女裝，用真的女人做
He's making himself a woman suit. Out of real women!
他還懂得縫紉
And he can sew!
他很熟練，他是個裁縫或...
He's very skilled. He's a tailor or a dressmaker or...
-史達琳！　-所以她們都身材肥大
- Starling! - That's why they're big.
他讓她們活著，逼使她們挨餓
He keeps them alive so he can starve them...
令她們的皮膚鬆弛，然後...
loosen their skin and...
史達琳，我們知道他的身份和下落
Starling! We know who and where he is!
我們快到達了
We're on our way right now.
-哪裡？　-芝加哥卡柳梅特城
- Where? - Calumet City, edge of Chicago.
我45分鐘後會和飛虎隊降落
Be on the ground in 45 minutes with HRT.
好消息，但怎麼...
That's great news, sir. But how...?
我們把約翰・霍金斯提供的名字，輸入已知犯人的檔案
We fed the names Johns Hopkins came up with into Known Offenders.
他叫傑米・甘姆，又名約翰・格蘭
Subject's name is Jamie Gumb, a.k.a. John Grant.
萊達的描述是正確的，他只是捏造那個名字
Lecter's description was accurate. He just lied about the name.
海關有些關於他的資料
Customs had some paper on him.
兩年前他們在洛杉磯機場，查到一個紙箱
They stopped a carton two years ago at LAX.
是一些來自蘇里南的活毛蟲
Live caterpillars from Suriname.
收件人叫詹米・甘姆
The addressee was a Jame Gumb.
芝加哥離這裡只有四百哩，我很快...
Chicago is only 400 miles from here. I'll be there in...
不，沒有時間了
No, there's not enough time.
我們要控告他謀殺，不是綁架
We want him for murder, not kidnapping.
在起訴他前，要找出他與費迪嘉・拜姆的關係
Link him to Bimmel before he's indicted.
-你去貝爾維迪爾看有什麼發現　-知道，我會盡力的
- See what you can find in Belvedere. - Yes, sir. You bet. I'll do my best.
史達琳
Starling.
沒有你我們就找不到他，大家都會記著這點
We wouldn't have found him without you. Nobody will forget that.
尤其是我
Least of all me.
謝謝，長官
Thank you, sir.
謝謝你，葛先生
Thank you very much, Mr. Crawford.
葛先生？
Mr. Crawford?
混蛋，謝謝那些冷飯菜汁
Thanks for the scraps, asshole.
我有更好的主意
I got a better idea.
珍寶，我來招呼你吧
Okay, Precious. Time for a little treat.
珍寶
Precious!
乖乖，來吧
Come on, girl!
來吧，珍寶，乖
Come on, Precious. Come on, Precious.
來吧，珍寶
Come on, Precious.
我有好吃的點心給你
I got a yummy, yummy snack for you.
來吃吧
Come and get it!
珍寶
Precious!
小畜牲，你在上面嗎？
Are you up there, you little shit?
快來吃啊，小寶貝
Come and get it, pretty girl.
珍寶
Precious!
求你來吧
Please come. Come on.
來吧，珍寶
Come on, Precious.
你想乾我嗎？
Would you fuck me?
來吃骨頭吧
Come on. Take that bone. Come on.
來吧...
Come on. Come on! Come on!
我想乾自己
I'd fuck me.
來吧
Come on.
我想狠狠的乾自己
I'd fuck me hard. I'd fuck me so hard.
不
No!
（國家空軍防衛隊總部）
伊利諾斯州芝加哥市
（莫斯里藥房）
當聯邦密探很棒吧？要經常出門的嗎？
Is that a good job, FBI agent? You get to travel around and stuff?
我是指去比這裡好的地方？
I mean, better places than this?
有時要的
Sometimes you do.
我找到這份銀行工作時，費迪很替我開心
Freddie was so happy for me when I got this job at the bank.
有烤麵包機贈品，整天播著巴尼曼尼羅的歌曲
Toaster giveaways and Barry Manilow on the speakers all day.
她覺得這是份苦差
She thought it was such hot shit.
她知道什麼？蠢才
What did she know? Big dummy.
史戴西，費迪可有提過一個叫傑米・甘姆的男人？
Stacy, did Fredrica ever mention a man named Jamie Gumb?
或者詹米・甘姆的人？
Or a Jame Gumb?
-約翰・格蘭呢？　-沒有
- How about John Grant? - No.
她有沒有一個你不認識的朋友？
Would she have had a friend you didn't know?
不可能，如果她有男朋友，我一定會知道
No way. If she had a guy, I'd have known.
縫紉是她的命根
Sewing was her life.
你們有一起工作嗎？
Did you ever work together?
我和瑪娜茜曾替她做利普曼太太的替工
Me and Pam Malavesi used to help her do alterations for old Mrs. Lippman.
可以把她的地址給我嗎？我要跟她談談
Can I get Mrs. Lippman's address? I need to talk to her.
（伊利諾斯州卡柳梅特城）
太有勁了
So powerful.
真的漂亮
So beautiful.
珍寶？
Precious?
這裡，混蛋！
Down here, you sack of shit!
-把它放在桶里　-不！
- Put her in that bucket. - No!
你立刻給我吊個電話下來
You get me a telephone and lower it down here, now!
乖乖，珍寶？你沒事吧？
Oh, poodlie-poo. Precious? Darling, are you all right?
她很痛苦，要找獸醫
She's in a lot of pain, mister. She needs a vet.
它下來時折斷了腿，它在舐...
She broke her leg on the way down. She's licking...
你別傷害我的狗
Hey! Don't you hurt my dog!
你別逼我傷害你的狗！
Don't you make me hurt your dog!
你不知道什麼是痛楚！
You don't know what pain is!
給我拿電話來，否則我殺死它！
Get me that telephone or I'll kill him!
-他媽的！　-你還是給我拿電話來
- Oh, fuck! - You better get me that telephone!
我要動手了
I'm gonna do it, mister!!
我會折斷它的頸，我發誓我會的
I'm gonna snap her neck off, I swear to God!
好的，先生，我要做了
All right, mister. I'm doing it!
好的，我來了
Okay, I'm coming.
我們進去
We're going in.
午安，抱歉打擾你
Good afternoon. Sorry to bother you.
我找利普曼太太的家人
I'm looking for Mrs. Lippman's family.
聯邦調查局！大家伏下！
FBI! Everybody down!
他們搬走了
Lippmans don't live here anymore.
對不起，先生，我要跟你談談
Excuse me, sir. I need to speak with you.
-沒有人　-沒有人
- Clear! - Clear!
有什麼問題呢？
What's the problem, officer?
我正在調查費迪嘉・拜姆的死因
I'm investigating the death of Fredrica Bimmel.
傑克，這裡沒人
There's no one here, Jack.
克麗絲
Clarice.
閣下是...
Your name is...?
傑克・戈登
Oh, Jack Gordon.
戈登先生，很好
Mr. Gordon. Good.
費迪是利普曼太太的僱員，你認識他嗎？
Fredrica worked for Mrs. Lippman. Did you know her?
不認識
No, uh-uh.
等一下
Oh, wait.
她是不是身材肥胖的？
Was she a great big fat person?
是，她很肥胖
Yes, she was a big girl, sir.
對，我可能有...
Yeah, I may have...
不，我在報紙上讀到她的新聞
No, I read about her in the newspaper.
利普曼太太有兒子，他或許可以幫忙
Mrs. Lippman had a son. Maybe he could help.
我這裡有他的名片
I got his card in here.
你要進來嗎？
You want to come in?
-可以嗎？　-當然可以
- May I? - Yeah, sure.
謝謝
Thank you.
你們很快會抓到人嗎？
Are you close to catching somebody?
是的
Yes.
或者吧
We may be.
你是不是...
Did you...
在利普曼太太死後搬到這裡來？
take over this place after Mrs. Lippman died, is that right?
是的，我兩年前買了這間屋
Yeah, I bought this house two years ago.
她有沒有留下任何記錄，業務記錄...
Did she leave any records, any business records...
稅單，僱員名單之類？
tax forms, lists of employees?
沒有，完全沒有
No, nothing like that at all.
聯邦調查局可有什麼發現？
Say, has the FBI learned something?
這裡的警方看來毫無頭緒
The police around here don't seem to have the first clue.
你們有沒有容貌，指紋之類的線索？
Have you got, like, a description, fingerprints, anything like that?
沒有
No.
我們沒有
No, we don't.
是這個電話號碼了
Here's that number.
很好
Very good, Mr. Gordon.
可否借用你的電話？
May I use your phone, please?
當然可以
Sure you can use my phone.
別動！
Freeze!
把雙手放在頭上，轉過來，張開腿
Put your hands over your head and turn around. Spread your legs.
張開腿
Spread your legs!
把雙手放在...
Put your hands in the back...
別動！
Freeze!
餵！
Hey!
你在嗎？
Are you there?
我在下面...
I'm down here! I'm down here!
凱瑟琳・馬丁？
Catherine Martin?
是！
Yes!
聯邦調查局
FBI.
你安全了
You're safe.
安全個屁！快救我出去
Safe, shit! Get me out of here!
你沒事的，他在哪裡？
You're all right. Where is he?
我怎麼知道？快救我出去！
How the fuck should I know? Just get me out of here!
凱瑟琳，你靜一點，叫那只狗別吵
Catherine, you've gotta be quiet! Now, shut that dog up!
快救我出去！
Just get me out of here!
我的天
Oh, my God.
凱瑟琳，我會救你的，但你聽著
Catherine, I'm gonna get you out. But right now, you listen to me.
我要離開一會，很快回來
I've gotta leave. I'll be right back
不，不要丟下我，你這個婊子，別走！
No! Don't you leave me here, you fucking bitch! No!
不要丟下我！
Don't you leave me here!
這個傢伙是瘋的！
This guy is fucking crazy!
等一下，我要離開這裡
Wait! I gotta get out of here!
求求你！
Please!
凱瑟琳！其他的探員會很快到達的
Catherine! The other officers will be here any minute now.
不要走！求求你
Wait! Don't go! Please!
別吵！
Quiet!
天啊...
Oh, God! Oh, God!
（恐怖）
（比爾剝下第五個人的皮）
-你沒事吧？　-小事，不要緊，我沒事
- You okay? - Gunpowder. It's nothing, I'm okay.
史達琳探員，你怎麼追查到水牛比爾在這裡的？
Agent Starling, how did you track Buffalo Bill here?
（司法部聯邦調查局）
克麗絲・史達琳
Clarice M. Starling.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
昂利・史蒂文
Ernest W. Stevens.
特種探員克麗絲・史達琳！
Special Agent Starling!
-特種探員麥普　-有電話找你
- Special Agent Mapp. - Phone call.
謝謝，失陪
Thank you. Excuse me.
史達琳
Starling.
替我們拍照好嗎？
Pilch, could you take our picture?
好的
Sure.
我只想說聲恭喜
I just wanted to say congratulations.
我不擅應酬，所以我要走了
I'm no good at this kind of thing, so I'm gonna duck out of here.
好的
Okay. Sure.
謝謝，葛先生
Thank you, Mr. Crawford.
令尊今天定會很驕傲
Your father would've been proud today.
別忘了接聽電話
Don't forget your phone call.
史達琳
Starling.
克麗絲...
Well, Clarice...
那些羔羊停止尖叫了嗎？
have the lambs stopped screaming?
萊達醫生？
Dr. Lecter?
不必追蹤這個電話，我不會講太久
Don't bother with a trace. I won't be on long enough.
萊達醫生，你在哪裡？
Where are you, Dr. Lecter?
我不打算找你了
I have no plans to call on you.
有了你，這個世界更加有趣
The world's more interesting with you in it.
你保重，日後報答我吧
So you take care now to extend me the same courtesy.
我不能作那個承諾的
You know I can't make that promise.
但願我們可以多聊一會
I do wish we could chat longer...
但我找了個老朋友吃晚飯
but I'm having an old friend for dinner.
再見
Bye.
萊達醫生！
Dr. Lecter!
萊達醫生
Dr. Lecter.
萊達醫生？
Dr. Lecter?
抱歉，對不起
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
保安系統安排了嗎？
The security system's set up?
-我們有嚴密保安的　-謝謝
- We have the big shot security. - I appreciate it.